<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>keep exceeding</title>
  
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://yoursite.com/"/>
  <updated>2019-04-18T13:42:13.116Z</updated>
  <id>http://yoursite.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>FancyXie</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>immunity_0418</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2019/04/18/0418-immunity/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2019/04/18/0418-immunity/</id>
    <published>2019-04-18T05:33:41.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-04-18T13:42:13.116Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Negative-Co-stimulation-Constrains-T-Cell-Differentiation-by-Imposing-Boundaries-on-Possible-Cell-States"><a href="#Negative-Co-stimulation-Constrains-T-Cell-Differentiation-by-Imposing-Boundaries-on-Possible-Cell-States" class="headerlink" title="Negative Co-stimulation Constrains T Cell Differentiation by Imposing Boundaries on Possible Cell States"></a>Negative Co-stimulation Constrains T Cell Differentiation by Imposing Boundaries on Possible Cell States</h2><p><a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.immuni.2019.03.004" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Negative Co-stimulation Constrains T Cell Differentiation by Imposing Boundaries on Possible Cell States</a></p><p>Immunity, 201904</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;h2 id=&quot;Negative-Co-stimulation-Constrains-T-Cell-Differentiation-by-Imposing-Boundaries-on-Possible-Cell-States&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Negative-Co-stim
      
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="daily" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/daily/"/>
    
    
      <category term="immunity" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/immunity/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Single-Cell Transcriptomics of Human and Mouse Lung Cancers Reveals Conserved Myeloid Populations across Individuals and Species</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2019/04/17/Single-Cell-Transcriptomics-of-Human-and-Mouse-Lung-Cancers-Reveals-Conserved-Myeloid-Populations-across-Individuals-and-Species/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2019/04/17/Single-Cell-Transcriptomics-of-Human-and-Mouse-Lung-Cancers-Reveals-Conserved-Myeloid-Populations-across-Individuals-and-Species/</id>
    <published>2019-04-17T11:48:56.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-04-17T15:31:48.394Z</updated>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="paper" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/paper/"/>
    
    
      <category term="immunity" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/immunity/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>tool</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2019/04/13/tool/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2019/04/13/tool/</id>
    <published>2019-04-13T14:29:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-04-18T06:39:51.557Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="CytoSPADE"><a href="#CytoSPADE" class="headerlink" title="CytoSPADE"></a>CytoSPADE</h2><blockquote><p>A high-performance implementation of an interface for the Spanning-tree Progression Analysis of Density-normalized Events algorithm for tree-based analysis and visualization of this high-dimensional cytometry data</p></blockquote><a id="more"></a><h2 id="PhenoGraph"><a href="#PhenoGraph" class="headerlink" title="PhenoGraph"></a>PhenoGraph</h2><blockquote><p><a href="http://www.cell.com/cell/abstract/S0092-8674(15" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PhenoGraph</a>00637-6) is a clustering method designed for high-dimensional single-cell data. It works by creating a graph (“network”) representing phenotypic similarities between cells and then identifying communities in this graph.</p></blockquote><p><a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/28865188" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PhenoGraph and viSNE facilitate the identification of abnormal T-cell populations in routine clinical flow cytometric data.</a></p><p><a href="https://www.cell.com/cell/fulltext/S0092-8674(15" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Data-Driven Phenotypic Dissection of AML Reveals Progenitor-like Cells that Correlate with Prognosis</a>00637-6&gt;)</p><h2 id="Louvain"><a href="#Louvain" class="headerlink" title="Louvain"></a>Louvain</h2><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/18/5cb81b8c5430c.jpg" alt></p><p><a href="https://sites.google.com/site/findcommunities/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Louvain method: Finding communities in large networks</a></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h2 id=&quot;CytoSPADE&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#CytoSPADE&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;CytoSPADE&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;CytoSPADE&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A high-performance implementation of an interface for the Spanning-tree Progression Analysis of Density-normalized Events algorithm for tree-based analysis and visualization of this high-dimensional cytometry data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="杂记" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/%E6%9D%82%E8%AE%B0/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The biology and function of fibroblasts in cancer</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2019/04/13/The-biology-and-function-of-fibroblasts-in-cancer/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2019/04/13/The-biology-and-function-of-fibroblasts-in-cancer/</id>
    <published>2019-04-13T07:51:43.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-04-15T15:49:23.377Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Abstract"><a href="#Abstract" class="headerlink" title="Abstract"></a>Abstract</h2><p>Fibroblasts are usually quiescent and become activated in a wound healing response. The governing principles of how quiescent, resting fibroblasts become ‘activated’ is still being unravelled, and exciting new information suggests that there might be two types of fibroblast activation profile: ‘reversible’ and ‘irreversible’, determined partly by epigenetic regulation. <font color="#F08080"><strong>Activated fibroblasts were identified predominantly by their expression of α-smooth muscle actin (αSMA; also known as ACTA2)</strong></font></p><p>(Fibroblast 一般是静默状态，在组织损伤时会被激活。activated fibroblast又可分为可逆的活化和不可逆的活化)</p><a id="more"></a><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/13/5cb19e719d889.jpg" alt="Multi-step activation of fibroblasts"></p><p>Resting fibroblasts may share many features with MSC precursors.</p><p>MSC(Mesenchymal stem cells 间充质干细胞)</p><h2 id="Quiescent-versus-activated-fibroblasts"><a href="#Quiescent-versus-activated-fibroblasts" class="headerlink" title="Quiescent versus activated fibroblasts"></a>Quiescent versus activated fibroblasts</h2><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/13/5cb1a2a3d2388.jpg" alt="Quiescent versus activated fibroblasts"></p><h2 id="Fibroblasts-and-mesenchymal-stem-cells"><a href="#Fibroblasts-and-mesenchymal-stem-cells" class="headerlink" title="Fibroblasts and mesenchymal stem cells"></a>Fibroblasts and mesenchymal stem cells</h2><p>it is well established that embryonic and umbilical cord‑derived fibroblasts and MSCs exhibit enhanced survival and stem cell‑like properties compared with those isolated from adult tissue. The collective evidence suggests that quiescent or resting fibroblasts are precursors of activated fibroblasts, which could also be called MSCs. Whether all activated fibroblasts are MSCs or only a subset that exhibits such properties remains to be determined and could depend on whether identical culture conditions are used</p><p>(activated fibroblast 也可称为MSC)</p><h2 id="Wound-healing-fibrosis-and-cancer"><a href="#Wound-healing-fibrosis-and-cancer" class="headerlink" title="Wound healing, fibrosis and cancer"></a>Wound healing, fibrosis and cancer</h2><h3 id="Acute-wound-healing"><a href="#Acute-wound-healing" class="headerlink" title="Acute wound healing"></a>Acute wound healing</h3><p>Once the wound is repaired, the number of activated fibroblasts decreases significantly owing to apoptosis, and the resting phenotype is probably restored. Such reversibility is the hallmark feature of tissue repair associated with wound healing.</p><h3 id="Cancer-fibrosis"><a href="#Cancer-fibrosis" class="headerlink" title="Cancer fibrosis"></a>Cancer fibrosis</h3><ul><li><p>Tumours are considered ‘wounds that do not heal’. Persistent emergence and accumulation of cancer cells in a given tissue represents an ongoing tissue injury, initiating a chronic wound healing response towards the cancer cells.(肿瘤可以被当成无法修复的组织损伤)</p></li><li><p>The term tumour fibrosis is interchangeable with desmoplastic reaction, tumour stroma and TME（结缔组织增生，肿瘤基质，TME）</p></li><li><p>Although the role of myofibroblasts in wound healing is well understood, their functional role in can- cer progression and metastasis is emerging as being complex and bimodal, with both cancer- promoting and cancer-restraining actions</p></li><li><p>The recruitment of stromal fibroblasts to the tumour is largely governed by the growth factors <strong>released by the cancer cells and the infiltrating immune cells</strong>. <font color="#F08080"><strong>TGFβ, PDGF and fibroblast growth factor 2 (FGF2)</strong></font> are key mediators of fibroblast activation in acute and chronic tissue damage. The recruitment of activated fibroblasts in many cancers is dependent on TGFβ</p></li><li><p>Many studies have shown that carcinoma in situ (CIS) already involves ‘reactive’ tumour fibrosis(原位癌时期就已经存在活化的fibroblast)。it might provide protection from invasive or<br>malignant conversion of CIS. Generally, the action of the cancer stroma is viewed as promoting cancer initiation and progression</p></li><li><p><font color="#F08080"><strong>IL-1β</strong></font> secretion by immune cells in early lesions emerges as a potential initiator of nuclear factor-κB (NF-κB) signalling in fibroblasts, instructing them to produce a pro-tumorigenic secretome</p></li><li><p>Reactive tumour stroma or fibrosis generally presents with an increased number of activated fibroblasts that usually express <font color="#F08080"><strong>αSMA or fibroblast activation protein (FAP)</strong></font> and exhibit increased deposition of collagens, fibrin and other ECM constituents compared with quies cent fibroblasts. The recruitment of new capillaries and accumulation of immune cells within the TME are mediated by many different growth factors, such as <font color="#F08080"><strong>VEGFA, PDGF, epidermal growth factor (EGF), IL-6 and IL-8</strong></font>, among others. In addition to cancer cell pro- duction of VEGFA, a source of host-derived VEGFA is activated fibroblasts.</p></li><li><p><font color="#F08080"><strong>Periostin and tenascin C</strong></font>, produced in part by activated fibroblasts, are generally absent in normal adult mammary tissue, but they become expressed in breast cancer</p></li></ul><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/13/5cb1cf191edda.jpg" alt="Fibroblasts are highly plastic and exhibit multipotency"></p><h2 id="Fibroblast-function-and-heterogeneity"><a href="#Fibroblast-function-and-heterogeneity" class="headerlink" title="Fibroblast function and heterogeneity"></a>Fibroblast function and heterogeneity</h2><ul><li><p>It is now clear that many different markers can identify activated fibroblasts. Such markers include <font color="#FF0000"><strong>fibroblast- specific protein 1 (FSP1; also known as S100A4), vimentin, αSMA, FAP, PDGF receptor-α (PDGFRα), PDGFRβ, desmin and discoidin domain-containing receptor 2 (DDR2)</strong></font>.Of note, PDGF receptors (PDGFRα and PDGFRβ) and the associated downstream signalling can be pharmacologically targeted . <strong>FSP1 is a reliable marker to detect quiescent, non-proliferating (Ki67−) fibroblasts</strong></p></li><li><p>但是这些marker都不是特异的，比如FSP1 also identifies macrophages and possibly other immune cells and is expressed by some cancer cells. FAP is also present in a subset of CD45+<br>immune cells. Desmin and PDGFRβ are also expressed in perivascular cells</p></li><li><p>Loss of caveolin 1 (<font color="#F08080"><strong>CAV1</strong></font>) expression in breast tumour CAFs may define metabolically altered fibroblasts with pro-tumorigenic functions, yet high expression of CAV1 in CAFs could also facilitate tumour invasion via ECM remodelling（乳腺癌中CAV1减少可促进癌症，但是增加会通过ECM重塑肿瘤的侵袭性）</p></li><li><p>The heterogeneity of fibroblasts, in particular those that are activated from their quiescent state, could also depend on the origin of the precursor fibroblasts. Activated fibroblasts are reported to arise from bone marrow-derived precursors, MSCs, endothelial cells, liver and pancreas stellate cells, resting tissue fibroblast and possibly from some types of epithelial cell(Fibroblast 的异质性与它的起源有关，相应的功能也可能有很大区别)</p><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/13/5cb1d2a8eb4af.jpg" alt="A proposed classification of subtypes of fibroblasts on the basis of function"></p><h3 id="Epigenetic-regulation-of-fibroblasts"><a href="#Epigenetic-regulation-of-fibroblasts" class="headerlink" title="Epigenetic regulation of fibroblasts"></a>Epigenetic regulation of fibroblasts</h3><ul><li>The signals that mediate the transition of resting fibroblasts into CAFs in tumours are probably complex, but in culture some of the phenotypic features associated with CAFs can be induced by TGFβ1. Nevertheless, emerging data suggest that the irreversible activation of fibroblasts might be driven by epigenetic alterations.(沉默Fibroblast向CAF转化的过程可能是由表观遗传调控的)</li></ul><ul><li>Studies with human breast tumours show that stromal cells (presumably fibroblasts) have unique epigenetic changes that are not observed in fibroblasts from normal mammary tissue</li><li>When FAFs are treated with the demethylating agent 5-azacytidine, the proliferation rate is reduced and collagen I synthesis and αSMA expression is decreased. Hypermethylation of RAS protein activator like 1 (RASAL1) and down regulation of RASAL1 protein lead to de novo activation of RAS in kidney FAFs but not in fibroblasts isolated from normal tissue or fibroblasts associated with acute kidney injury(使用去甲基化药物后，肿瘤中胶原减少，αSMA减少。RASAL1的过甲基化激活肾脏FAF中的RAS)</li><li>Prostate stromal cells with <strong>over-expression</strong> of the epigenetic regulator high-mobility group AT-hook 2 (<font color="#FF0000"><strong>HMGA2</strong></font>) were sufficient to induce prostatic intraepithelial neoplasia</li><li>An epigenetic switch implicating the regulation of leukaemia inhibitory factor (LIF) may result in the <strong>sustained and proinvasive functions</strong> of CAFs, via enhanced Janus kinase 1 ( <font color="#F08080"><strong>JAK1</strong></font>)–signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 ( <font color="#F08080"><strong>STAT3</strong></font>) activation</li></ul><h2 id="CAFs-positive-regulators-of-cancer"><a href="#CAFs-positive-regulators-of-cancer" class="headerlink" title="CAFs: positive regulators of cancer"></a>CAFs: positive regulators of cancer</h2><h3 id="CAFs-in-tumorigenesis"><a href="#CAFs-in-tumorigenesis" class="headerlink" title="CAFs in tumorigenesis"></a>CAFs in tumorigenesis</h3><p>The ability of CAFs to influence tumour growth was partly dependent on their ability to induce angiogenesis by CAF- derived stromal cell-derived factor 1 (SDF1; also known as <font color="#FF0000"><strong>CXCL12</strong></font>)</p></li></ul>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h2 id=&quot;Abstract&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Abstract&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Abstract&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fibroblasts are usually quiescent and become activated in a wound healing response. The governing principles of how quiescent, resting fibroblasts become ‘activated’ is still being unravelled, and exciting new information suggests that there might be two types of fibroblast activation profile: ‘reversible’ and ‘irreversible’, determined partly by epigenetic regulation. &lt;font color=&quot;#F08080&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activated fibroblasts were identified predominantly by their expression of α-smooth muscle actin (αSMA; also known as ACTA2)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Fibroblast 一般是静默状态，在组织损伤时会被激活。activated fibroblast又可分为可逆的活化和不可逆的活化)&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="paper" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/paper/"/>
    
    
      <category term="cancer" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/cancer/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>0413_RNAseq</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2019/04/13/0413-RNAseq/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2019/04/13/0413-RNAseq/</id>
    <published>2019-04-13T05:47:04.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-04-13T11:37:18.402Z</updated>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>0412-immunity</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2019/04/12/0412-immunity/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2019/04/12/0412-immunity/</id>
    <published>2019-04-12T13:34:49.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-04-13T11:37:07.027Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="HSAN-I-相关SPTLC2缺失通过抑制T-细胞代谢抑制CD8-T细胞对于感染的反应"><a href="#HSAN-I-相关SPTLC2缺失通过抑制T-细胞代谢抑制CD8-T细胞对于感染的反应" class="headerlink" title="HSAN-I 相关SPTLC2缺失通过抑制T 细胞代谢抑制CD8 T细胞对于感染的反应"></a>HSAN-I 相关SPTLC2缺失通过抑制T 细胞代谢抑制CD8 T细胞对于感染的反应</h2><p><a href="https://www.cell.com/immunity/fulltext/S1074-7613(19" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Loss of Neurological Disease HSAN-I-Associated Gene <em>SPTLC2</em> Impairs CD8+ T Cell Responses to Infection by Inhibiting T Cell Metabolic Fitness</a>)</p><p>Immmunity, 2019.03</p><a id="more"></a><p>SPTLC2(serine palmitoyltransferase subunit)</p><p>SPTLC2 mutations are associated with the neurological disorder HSAN-I, in which patients get frequent infections, attributed to loss of pain sensation and failure to seek treatment for minor injuries. Wu et al. show that protective CD8+ T cell responses are defective in HSAN-I patients and that CD8+ T cells require SPTLC2-mediated sphingolipid synthesis to promote T cell metabolic fitness.</p><p><em>Sptlc2</em> deficiency reduced <strong>sphingolipid biosynthetic flux and led to prolonged activation of the mechanistic target of rapamycin complex 1 (mTORC1), endoplasmic reticulum (ER) stress, and CD8 + T cell death</strong>. Protective CD8 + T cell responses in HSAN-I patient PBMCs and <em>Sptlc2</em>-deficient mice were restored by supplementing with sphingolipids and pharmacologically inhibiting ER stress-induced cell death. Therefore, SPTLC2 underpins protective immunity by translating extracellular stimuli into intracellular anabolic signals and antagonizes ER stress to promote T cell metabolic fitness.</p><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/12/5cb073b2d43d4.jpg" alt></p><h2 id="角质形成细胞介导的TGF-β活化维持皮肤对于记忆性CD8-T-细胞的招募"><a href="#角质形成细胞介导的TGF-β活化维持皮肤对于记忆性CD8-T-细胞的招募" class="headerlink" title="角质形成细胞介导的TGF-β活化维持皮肤对于记忆性CD8 T 细胞的招募"></a>角质形成细胞介导的TGF-β活化维持皮肤对于记忆性CD8 T 细胞的招募</h2><p><a href="https://www.cell.com/immunity/fulltext/S1074-7613(19" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Keratinocyte-Mediated Activation of the Cytokine TGF-β Maintains Skin Recirculating Memory CD8+ T Cells</a>)</p><p>Regulated activation of the cytokine TGF-β by integrins α vβ 6 and α vβ 8 expressed on keratinocytes is required for residence of epidermal-resident memory T cells, but whether skin-derived signals also affect recirculating memory cells in the skin remains unclear. Here, we show that <strong>after resolution of skin vaccinia virus (VV) infection, antigen-specific circulating memory CD8 + T cells migrated into skin</strong>. In mice lacking α vβ 6 and α vβ 8 integrins ( <em>Itgb6</em> −/− <em>Itgb8</em> fl/fl <em>-</em>K14-cre), the absence of epidermal-activated TGF-β resulted in a gradual loss of E- or P-selectin-binding central and peripheral memory populations, which were rescued when skin entry was inhibited. Skin recirculating memory cells were required for optimal host defense against skin VV infection. These data demonstrate that skin migration can persist after resolution of local skin infection and that the cytokine environment within this nonlymphoid tissue shapes the differentiation state and persistence of the central and peripheral memory-T-cell pool.</p><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/12/5cb07f58b3da3.jpg" alt></p><h2 id="cDC1的一个亚群通过VEGFα介导的对于中性粒细胞的募集控制皮肤感染"><a href="#cDC1的一个亚群通过VEGFα介导的对于中性粒细胞的募集控制皮肤感染" class="headerlink" title="cDC1的一个亚群通过VEGFα介导的对于中性粒细胞的募集控制皮肤感染"></a>cDC1的一个亚群通过VEGFα介导的对于中性粒细胞的募集控制皮肤感染</h2><p><a href="https://www.cell.com/immunity/fulltext/S1074-7613(19" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A Subset of Type I Conventional Dendritic Cells Controls Cutaneous Bacterial Infections through VEGFα-Mediated Recruitment of Neutrophils</a>)</p><p>皮肤常规树突细胞（cDC）有两种不同的子集cDC1和cDC2存在，从而维持对病原体的免疫和对自身微生物群耐受的平衡。本文作者检测了皮肤cDC1s和cDC2s在细菌尤其是痤疮丙酸杆菌感染期间的作用。 cDC1s，而不是cDC2s，通过控制炎症部位的中性粒细胞募集及其存活和功能来调节对真皮中痤疮丙酸杆菌的免疫应答的程度。单细胞mRNA测序显示，该调节依赖于由一小部分活化的<font color="#F08080"><strong>EpCAM + CD59 + Ly-6D + cDC1s</strong></font>细胞分泌的细胞因子<font color="#F08080"><strong>VEGF-α</strong></font>。在金黄色葡萄球菌，卡介苗或大肠杆菌感染期间以及在人皮肤中的细菌损伤模型中也观察到真皮cDC1对中性粒细胞的募集作用。因此，皮肤cDC1是皮肤免疫中先天反应的必需调节剂，并且具有超出经典抗原呈递的作用。</p><p>In the skin, two subsets of ontogenetically distinct and functionally specialized conventional DCs (cDCs) exist: cDC1s, identified in mice as expressing <font color="#F08080"><strong>CD103 (integrin aE) and XCR1</strong></font>; and cDC2s, expressing <font color="#F08080"><strong>CD11b (integrin aM) and SIRPa</strong></font></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h2 id=&quot;HSAN-I-相关SPTLC2缺失通过抑制T-细胞代谢抑制CD8-T细胞对于感染的反应&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#HSAN-I-相关SPTLC2缺失通过抑制T-细胞代谢抑制CD8-T细胞对于感染的反应&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;HSAN-I 相关SPTLC2缺失通过抑制T 细胞代谢抑制CD8 T细胞对于感染的反应&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;HSAN-I 相关SPTLC2缺失通过抑制T 细胞代谢抑制CD8 T细胞对于感染的反应&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cell.com/immunity/fulltext/S1074-7613(19&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Loss of Neurological Disease HSAN-I-Associated Gene &lt;em&gt;SPTLC2&lt;/em&gt; Impairs CD8+ T Cell Responses to Infection by Inhibiting T Cell Metabolic Fitness&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immmunity, 2019.03&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="daily" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/daily/"/>
    
    
      <category term="immunity" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/immunity/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Serine Metabolism Supports Macrophage IL-1b production</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2019/04/12/Serine-Metabolism-Supports-Macrophage-IL-1b-production/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2019/04/12/Serine-Metabolism-Supports-Macrophage-IL-1b-production/</id>
    <published>2019-04-12T08:02:30.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-04-13T11:37:35.732Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2019.01.014" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Serine Metabolism Supports Macrophage IL-1b Production </a></p><a id="more"></a><p> <img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/12/5cb043518e049.jpg" alt></p><p>&nbsp;</p><h2 id="highlight"><a href="#highlight" class="headerlink" title="highlight"></a>highlight</h2><ul><li>Serine deprivation diminishes LPS-induced IL-1b mRNA expression </li><li>LPS stimulates serine generation of glycine for glutathione synthesis</li><li>Glutathione is necessary to maintain LPS induction of IL-1bproduction </li><li>Inhibition of de novo serine synthesis promotes survival of mice exposed to LPS </li></ul><h2 id="Result"><a href="#Result" class="headerlink" title="Result"></a>Result</h2><h3 id="Serine-Is-Necessary-for-Optimal-IL-1b-Gene-Expression"><a href="#Serine-Is-Necessary-for-Optimal-IL-1b-Gene-Expression" class="headerlink" title="Serine Is Necessary for Optimal IL-1b Gene Expression"></a>Serine Is Necessary for Optimal IL-1b Gene Expression</h3><p> <img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/12/5cb0450d4943f.jpg" alt></p><p>ECAR:胞外产酸能力，间接反映糖酵解水平</p><p>OCR：检测耗氧量</p><p>&nbsp;</p><h3 id="Serine-Metabolism-Supports-LPS-Induction-of-GSH-synthesis-which-Is-Required-for-IL-1b-Gene-Expression"><a href="#Serine-Metabolism-Supports-LPS-Induction-of-GSH-synthesis-which-Is-Required-for-IL-1b-Gene-Expression" class="headerlink" title="Serine Metabolism Supports LPS Induction of GSH synthesis, which Is Required for IL-1b Gene Expression"></a>Serine Metabolism Supports LPS Induction of GSH synthesis, which Is Required for IL-1b Gene Expression</h3><p> <img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/12/5cb045235a5a2.jpg" alt></p><p>&nbsp;</p><h3 id="Serine-Deprivation-Diminishes-IL-1b-Gene-Expression-of-BMDMs-without-Altering-Inflammation-Associated-Gene-Networks-or-Inflammasome-Activation"><a href="#Serine-Deprivation-Diminishes-IL-1b-Gene-Expression-of-BMDMs-without-Altering-Inflammation-Associated-Gene-Networks-or-Inflammasome-Activation" class="headerlink" title="Serine Deprivation Diminishes IL-1b Gene Expression of BMDMs without Altering Inflammation-Associated Gene Networks or Inflammasome Activation"></a>Serine Deprivation Diminishes IL-1b Gene Expression of BMDMs without Altering Inflammation-Associated Gene Networks or Inflammasome Activation</h3><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/12/5cb044648650a.jpg" alt></p><p>&nbsp;</p><h3 id="De-Novo-Serine-Synthesis-Is-Required-for-LPS-Responses-In-Vivo"><a href="#De-Novo-Serine-Synthesis-Is-Required-for-LPS-Responses-In-Vivo" class="headerlink" title="De Novo Serine Synthesis Is Required for LPS Responses In Vivo"></a>De Novo Serine Synthesis Is Required for LPS Responses In Vivo</h3><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/12/5cb044d36de7c.jpg" alt></p><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cmet.2019.01.014&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Serine Metabolism Supports Macrophage IL-1b Production &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="paper" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/paper/"/>
    
    
      <category term="immunity" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/immunity/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>fibroblast in cancer</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2019/04/09/fibroblast%20in%20cancer/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2019/04/09/fibroblast in cancer/</id>
    <published>2019-04-09T06:53:51.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-04-13T11:37:22.535Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="doi:10.1038/nrc1877" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fibroblasts in cancer</a></p><p>The important functions of fibroblasts include the deposition of extracellular matrix (ECM), regulation of epithelial differentiation, regulation of inflammation, and involvement in wound healing</p><a id="more"></a><h2 id="The-tumour-stroma"><a href="#The-tumour-stroma" class="headerlink" title="The tumour stroma"></a>The tumour stroma</h2><p>Normal stroma in most organs contains a minimal number of fibroblasts in association with a physiological ECM. Reactive stroma is associated with an increased number of fibroblasts, enhanced capillary density, and type-I-collagen and fibrin deposition.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/09/5cac5243ebdef.jpg" alt></p><p>In chickens that are cancer-prone because they have been infected with Rous sarcoma virus, wounding leads to invasive carcinomas within tissues that would other- wise remain tumour-free. This demonstrates that reactive stroma provides oncogenic signals to facilitate tumorigenesis.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF, also known as vascular permeability factor (VPF)) has a central role in the emergence of the reactive stroma</p><p><strong>VEGF induces microvascular permeability</strong>, which leads to the extravasation of plasma proteins such as fibrin, which in turn attract an influx of fibroblasts, inflammatory cells and endothelial cells. These cells produce ECM(extracellular matrix) that is rich in fibronectin and type I collagen, both of which are conducive to initiating tumour angiogenesis</p><p>carcinoma in situ (CIS)</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p><strong>Tenascin C</strong> is absent in the normal adult mammary gland, but  expression is regularly seen in mammary tumours. Increased tenascin-C expression correlates with poor prognosis for both <strong>breast cancer and bladder cancer</strong>.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>There are several well-established indicators of fibroblast phenotype, but none of them are both exclusive to fibroblasts and present in all fibroblasts (see table). Among all of the known markers, fibroblast-specific protein 1 (<strong>FSP1</strong>) seems to provide the best specificity for detecting fibroblasts in vivo. <strong>Desmin</strong> is a specific marker for fibroblasts in the skin, whereas it is strongly expressed in muscle cells in other sites</p><p>Fetal skin fibroblasts express high levels of collagen types I and V, whereas fetal lung fibroblasts do not. Also, fetal lung fibroblasts exclusively express the lung-specific forkhead family transcription factors <strong>FOXF1</strong> and <strong>FOXP1</strong></p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Injection of <strong>L-3,4 dehydroproline</strong> (which inhibits the formation of collagen fibrils) increases tumour cell invasion in a mouse model of B16F10 melanoma subcutaneous tumours</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/09/5cacbb9c1f275.jpg" alt></p><p>&nbsp;</p><h2 id="Carcinoma-associated-fibroblasts"><a href="#Carcinoma-associated-fibroblasts" class="headerlink" title="Carcinoma-associated fibroblasts"></a>Carcinoma-associated fibroblasts</h2><p>In the absence of electron microscopy validation, CAFs are commonly identified by their expression of <font color="#F08080"><strong>α-smooth-muscle actin</strong></font></p><p>The signals that mediate the transition of a normal fibroblast into a CAF are not fully understood. In culture, phenotypic features of CAFs can be induced by transforming growth factor-β (TGFβ), which mediates fibroblast activation during wound healing and organ fibrosis.Therefore, similar pathways might also be responsible for the emergence of CAFs in tumours.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/09/5cacbbf68b1dc.jpg" alt></p><p>&nbsp;</p><h2 id="Growth-factors-and-fibroblasts"><a href="#Growth-factors-and-fibroblasts" class="headerlink" title="Growth factors and fibroblasts"></a>Growth factors and fibroblasts</h2><p>Tumour stroma volume and composition are partly governed by the response of fibroblasts to the pro-fibrotic growth factors that are released by the cancer cells— for example, TGFβ, platelet-derived growth factor (PDGF) and fibroblast growth factor 2 (FGF2)</p><p>PDGF is another growth factor that is secreted by can- cer cells and correlates with cancer progression.As opposed to TGFβ, PDGF induces the proliferation of fibroblasts, but does not induce the acquisition of an activated phenotype that is associated with excessive ECM deposition</p><p>&nbsp;</p><h2 id="EMT-as-a-source-of-CAFs"><a href="#EMT-as-a-source-of-CAFs" class="headerlink" title="EMT as a source of CAFs"></a>EMT as a source of CAFs</h2><p>In epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition (EMT), epithelial cells lose cell–cell contacts and acquire mesenchymal properties. Cancer cells undergoing EMT develop invasive and migratory abilities</p><p>EMT involving normal epithelial cells that are adjacent to malignant cancer cells might also contribute to the emergence of CAFs</p><p>&nbsp;</p><h2 id="The-role-of-CAFs-in-the-initiation-of-cancer"><a href="#The-role-of-CAFs-in-the-initiation-of-cancer" class="headerlink" title="The role of CAFs in the initiation of cancer"></a>The role of CAFs in the initiation of cancer</h2><p>Overexpression of TGFβ and/or hepatocyte growth factor (<font color="#F08080"><strong>HGF</strong></font>) in mouse fibroblasts induces the initiation of breast cancer within the normal human epithelium.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/12/5cb0933d9c560.jpg" alt></p><p>&nbsp;</p><h2 id="The-role-of-CAFs-in-the-progression-of-cancer"><a href="#The-role-of-CAFs-in-the-progression-of-cancer" class="headerlink" title="The role of CAFs in the progression of cancer"></a>The role of CAFs in the progression of cancer</h2><p>Ras-transformed human MCF-7 breast cancer cells (which form tumours and metastasize independent of oestrogen) were co-injected subcutaneously into nude mice in suspension with CAFs or normal fibroblasts The results showed that xenografts containing CAFs grew larger than xenografts infused with normal fibroblasts<br>Such enhanced growth was associated with increased cancer-cell proliferation (but not increased fibroblast pro- liferation) and more angiogenesis, indicating that CAFs might have a bi-modal effect during tumorigenesis</p><p>既能促进癌细胞的增殖，又能促进血管的生成</p><p>CAF-derived stromal- cell-derived factor 1 (<font color="#F08080"><strong>SDF1</strong></font>) mediates the recruitment of bone-marrow-derived endothelial cells and directly increases the proliferation of MCF-Ras cancer cells</p><p>Activated fibroblasts are a source of ECM-degrading proteases such as the MMPs. MMPs probably allow cancer cells to cross tissue boundaries and escape the primary tumour site.</p><font color="#F08080"><strong>MMP3</strong></font> (also known as stromelysin 1) is highly expressed in fibroblasts<br><br>MMP3 directly cleaves the extra- cellular domain of E-cadherin, prompting normal mammary epithelial cells to disaggregate and undergo EMT, promoting cancer-cell invasiveness. MMP1 also shows such a tumour-promoting effect. The protease-activated receptor <font color="#F08080"><strong>PAR1</strong></font>, which is a tethered-ligand receptor, is activated by proteolytic cleavage of the extracellular domain by MMP1, promoting cancer cell migration and invasion through PAR1-dependent Ca2+ signals<br><br>(MMP3和MMP1切割E-钙黏蛋白的胞外结构域，从而激活PAR1。PAR1通过Ca2+信号促进癌细胞的迁移)<br><br>&nbsp;<br><br>## The role of CAFs in metastasis<br><br>only the melanoma cells that metastasized were influenced by fibroblasts. This indicates that specific stimuli provided by fibroblasts create a niche that promotes the growth of subsets of cancer cells at distant sites. Tumour growth and metastasis in FSP1-deficient mice (FSP1-deficient fibroblasts show decreased motility) is significantly reduced.<br><br>&nbsp;&nbsp;<br><br>## Fibroblasts and TGFβ<br><br>TGFβ has a role in the recruitment of fibroblasts. However, TGFβ is also the most prominent of the factors within the tumour micro- environment that are known to induce EMT of cancer cells. Before the initiation of cancer, and during the early stages of carcinogenesis, TGFβ probably functions as a tumour suppressor. By contrast, during advanced stages of cancer, TGFβ signalling promotes cancer progression and metastasis.<br><br>In normal tissues, the anti-proliferative and proapoptotic response of epithelial cells to TGFβ might limit the growth of normal epithelium and the emergence of malignant carcinomas. With regard to fibroblasts,TGFβ facilitates fibroblast–epithelial-cell interactions, which further suppress cancer initiation. In advanced cancer, on the other hand, the anti-proliferative effect of TGFβ is progressively lost — instead, it facilitates EMT of cancer cells, potentially promoting invasiveness and metastasis. Signalling pathways that are implicated in TGFβ-mediated EMT involve  <font color="#F08080"><strong>Smad</strong></font> signalling, the <font color="#F08080"><strong>phosphatidylinositol-3-kinase–Akt</strong></font> pathway and signalling through <font color="#F08080"><strong>RHOA</strong></font> and <font color="#F08080"><strong>p38 MAPK</strong></font><p>(其中Smad可能是起决定作用的通路)</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/12/5cb0937f9bfc0.jpg" alt></p><p>&nbsp;</p><h2 id="Fibroblasts-in-the-host-defence-against-cancer"><a href="#Fibroblasts-in-the-host-defence-against-cancer" class="headerlink" title="Fibroblasts in the host defence against cancer?"></a>Fibroblasts in the host defence against cancer?</h2><p>Fibroblasts that overexpress TGFβ and HGF promote tumorigenic outgrowth of normal breast epithelium, but such outgrowth is inhibited by ‘normal’ stromal fibroblasts. One possible mechanism for such a function of fibroblasts in host defence is modulation of the immune response. Fibroblasts are a signficant source of immune-modulatory cytokines such as interferon-γ, interleukin-6 and tumour-necrosis factor-α which can influence the mobilization of cytotoxic T lymphocytes, natural killer cells and macrophages. In this regard, it has also been suggested that normal fibroblasts help to prevent apoptosis of T cells</p><p>(活化的fibroblast促进癌症，normal fibroblast抑制癌症)</p><p>&nbsp;</p><h2 id="Therapies-to-target-activated-fibroblasts"><a href="#Therapies-to-target-activated-fibroblasts" class="headerlink" title="Therapies to target activated fibroblasts"></a>Therapies to target activated fibroblasts</h2><p>Fibroblast-directed therapy can be envisioned as either ‘to ablate’ or ‘to normalize’ CAFs. The cell-surface serine protease known as fibroblast activation protein (<font color="#F08080"><strong>FAP</strong></font>) emerges as a promising candidate for specifically targetting CAFs. FAP is not expressed by mature somatic tissues except for activated fibroblasts during wound healing and within tumour stroma.</p><p>HGF inhibits the activation and progression of tissue fibrosis in several animal models of chronic disease, and HGF overexpression prevents fibrosis in the liver and kidneys. However, numerous studies have implied that HGF promotes the malignant transformation of epithelial cells and also promotes cancer progression</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;doi:10.1038/nrc1877&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Fibroblasts in cancer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important functions of fibroblasts include the deposition of extracellular matrix (ECM), regulation of epithelial differentiation, regulation of inflammation, and involvement in wound healing&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="paper" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/paper/"/>
    
    
      <category term="cancer" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/cancer/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>singleR</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2019/04/01/singleR/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2019/04/01/singleR/</id>
    <published>2019-04-01T05:28:15.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-04-18T16:34:54.675Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41590-018-0276-y" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Reference-based analysis of lung single-cell sequencing reveals a transitional profibrotic macrophage</a></p><h2 id="Results"><a href="#Results" class="headerlink" title="Results"></a>Results</h2><h3 id="Reference-data-sets-enhance-annotation-of-scRNA-seq"><a href="#Reference-data-sets-enhance-annotation-of-scRNA-seq" class="headerlink" title="Reference data sets enhance annotation of scRNA-seq"></a>Reference data sets enhance annotation of scRNA-seq</h3><h4 id="Pipeline"><a href="#Pipeline" class="headerlink" title="Pipeline"></a>Pipeline</h4><p>The SingleR pipeline is based on correlating reference <strong>bulk transcriptomic data sets of pure cell types</strong> with single-cell gene expression.In the first step of the SingleR pipeline, a <strong>Spearman coefficient</strong> was calculated for single-cell gene expression with each of the samples in the reference data set, <strong>using only the variable genes in the reference data set</strong>. Using only variable genes among the cell types increased the ability to distinguish closely related cell types. This process was performed iteratively using only the top cell types from the previous step and the variable genes among them until only one cell type remaine</p><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/03/31/5ca058a40ec09.jpg" alt="Pipeline of singleR"></p><a id="more"></a><h4 id="Validate-SingleR"><a href="#Validate-SingleR" class="headerlink" title="Validate SingleR"></a>Validate SingleR</h4><p>Using SingleR to analyze a published study of scRNA-seq of mouse bone marrow-derived dendritic cells (BMDC) and fibroblasts. When applied to the ImmGen database as a reference library, SingleR identified 33 of the 48 cells thought in the study to be BMDCs as macrophages</p><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/03/31/5ca06b69ebecd.jpg" alt></p><p>原文中用GM-CSF培养细胞，然后sorting CD11c+ 的细胞。这个protocol已被证明无法获得纯的DC细胞，会混进表达marcrophage markers的细胞。</p><h3 id="SingleR-identifies-a-transitional-macrophage-in-fibrosis"><a href="#SingleR-identifies-a-transitional-macrophage-in-fibrosis" class="headerlink" title="SingleR identifies a transitional macrophage in fibrosis"></a>SingleR identifies a transitional macrophage in fibrosis</h3><p>applied SingleR to enhance annotation of a lung scRNA-seq data set obtained from whole lungs of adult, male mice (10–12 weeks age) dissociated into single-cell suspension and flow sorted on live cells, using 6 steady-state mice and 3 mice 14 days after a single tracheal instillation of bleomycin, the fibrotic phase of the injury model.</p><p>  <img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/01/5ca1a1e0bff7b.jpg" alt></p><p><strong>conclusion:</strong> The number of lung macrophages was higher in the bleomycin-treated condition than at steady state</p><p>Macrophages and dendritic cells have similar transcriptomic profiles. So the authors repeated SingleR analysis using published RNA-seq data sets of mouse lung macrophages and dendritic cells to isolate the macrophages in the pooled bleomycin-injured and steady-state samples. Finally, singleR identified two subtypes of macrophages: alveolar and interstitial macrophages</p><p>Similarity analysis by comparison of each cell to mouse RNA-seq data sets of alveolar and interstitial macrophages indicated a gradient of cellular identity in the macrophage cluster between alveolar and interstitial macrophages</p><p>Deconvolution analysis in was performed using the DeconRNA-seq package using the average expression of AM samples and average expression of IM3 samples from GSE94135</p><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/01/5ca1a243a8188.jpg" alt></p><p>Then, the full range of SingleR correlation scores for each cell with reference to ImmGen was used for unsupervised hierarchical clustering of the macrophages from the lung scRNA-seq data set. This analysis identified three distinct subclusters (C1, C2, and C3), all three detected at varying levels in both steady-state and bleomycin-treated mice.45% of cluster C2 cells (but only 7.3% of cluster C1 cells and 4.7% of cluster C3 cells) expressed at least 33% of cluster C1 genes and at least 33% of cluster C3 genes, suggesting that cluster C2 was intermediate in gene expression between C1 and C3</p><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/01/5ca1a2ee98ae4.jpg" alt="Hierarchical clustering by reference annotation reveals a transitional macrophage in fibrosis"></p><p><strong>conclusion:</strong>cluster C1 was equally present in steady-state lung and bleomycin injury and corresponded to the cells that were annotated as alveolar macrophages by the lung-specific data sets; clusters C2 and C3 were enriched in cells isolated from mice with bleomycin-induced fibrosis and expressed Cx3cr1, Ccr2, Mafb, and MHCII genes, consistent with monocytic origin</p><p>Clustering in Fig. 3a was performed using <strong>Ward’s hierarchical agglomerative clustering method</strong> based on the SingleR scores across all cell types</p><h3 id="Cluster-C2-and-C3-markers-are-found-in-alternate-lung-fibrosis-models"><a href="#Cluster-C2-and-C3-markers-are-found-in-alternate-lung-fibrosis-models" class="headerlink" title="Cluster C2 and C3 markers are found in alternate lung fibrosis models"></a>Cluster C2 and C3 markers are found in alternate lung fibrosis models</h3><p>To test the relevance of the identified gene expression pat-tern to other models of fibrosis, the authors used a mouse model of lung fibrosis induced by epithelial telomere dysfunction</p><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/01/5ca1a38c303d7.jpg" alt="Markers of macrophages identified by scRNA-seq are found in multiple fibrosis models"></p><p>用human芯片数据验证，发现在小鼠中得出的结论也使用与人.immunofluorescence of lung tissue indicated the expression of <strong>MAFB</strong>, a marker detected specifically in clusters C2 and C3, in CD68+  macrophages from patients with idiopathic lung fibrosis compared with healthy controls(Figc)</p><h3 id="Cluster-C2-macrophages-localize-to-the-fibrotic-niche"><a href="#Cluster-C2-macrophages-localize-to-the-fibrotic-niche" class="headerlink" title="Cluster C2 macrophages localize to the fibrotic niche"></a>Cluster C2 macrophages localize to the fibrotic niche</h3><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/01/5ca1a510967d7.jpg" alt="transitional macrophages expressing CX3CR1, MHCII, and SiglecF localize to sites of fibroblast accumulation after lung injury"></p><p><strong>Conclusion:</strong> macrophage cluster C2 localizes to the fibrotic niche</p><h3 id="CX3CR1-expressing-macrophages-drive-lung-fibrosis"><a href="#CX3CR1-expressing-macrophages-drive-lung-fibrosis" class="headerlink" title="CX3CR1-expressing macrophages drive lung fibrosis"></a>CX3CR1-expressing macrophages drive lung fibrosis</h3><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2019/04/01/5ca1a56682dfe.jpg" alt="Pdgf-aa is a macrophage-derived trophic factor for fibroblasts"></p><p><strong>Conclusion：</strong>during fibrogenesis, CX3CR1+ SiglecF+ macrophages localize to sites of Pdgfra+ and Pdgfrb+ fibroblast accumulation after bleomycin-induced injury in the lung. Deletion of these macrophages during the fibrotic period (days 8–21) eliminated Pdgfra+ or Pdgfrb+ fibroblasts and decreased total lung collagen. Mechanistic studies indicated that fibroblast migration and proliferation were dependent on secretion of Pdgf-aa by SiglecF+ CD11c+ MHCIIhi and CX3CR1+ cells, respectively, suggesting that paracrine interactions between these macrophages and fibroblasts sustain the fibroblast compartment and tissue fibrosis.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41590-018-0276-y&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Reference-based analysis of lung single-cell sequencing reveals a transitional profibrotic macrophage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Results&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Results&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Results&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&quot;Reference-data-sets-enhance-annotation-of-scRNA-seq&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Reference-data-sets-enhance-annotation-of-scRNA-seq&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Reference data sets enhance annotation of scRNA-seq&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Reference data sets enhance annotation of scRNA-seq&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&quot;Pipeline&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Pipeline&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Pipeline&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Pipeline&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The SingleR pipeline is based on correlating reference &lt;strong&gt;bulk transcriptomic data sets of pure cell types&lt;/strong&gt; with single-cell gene expression.In the first step of the SingleR pipeline, a &lt;strong&gt;Spearman coefficient&lt;/strong&gt; was calculated for single-cell gene expression with each of the samples in the reference data set, &lt;strong&gt;using only the variable genes in the reference data set&lt;/strong&gt;. Using only variable genes among the cell types increased the ability to distinguish closely related cell types. This process was performed iteratively using only the top cell types from the previous step and the variable genes among them until only one cell type remaine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.loli.net/2019/03/31/5ca058a40ec09.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pipeline of singleR&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="paper" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/paper/"/>
    
    
      <category term="methods" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/methods/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Neoantigen-directed immune escape in lung cancer evolution</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2019/03/30/Neoantigen-directed-immune-escape-in-lung-cancer-evolution/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2019/03/30/Neoantigen-directed-immune-escape-in-lung-cancer-evolution/</id>
    <published>2019-03-30T12:39:32.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-04-13T11:37:26.679Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>[Neoantigen-directed immune escape in lung cancer evolution] (<a href="https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-019-1032-7" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-019-1032-7</a>)</p><h1 id="Topic"><a href="#Topic" class="headerlink" title="Topic"></a>Topic</h1><p>To determine immune infiltration in untreated non-small-cell lung cancer (NSCLC), assess how this infiltration varies between and within tumours, and characterize immune-evasion mechanisms and their associations with clinical outcome.</p><a id="more"></a><h1 id="Sample"><a href="#Sample" class="headerlink" title="Sample"></a>Sample</h1><p>Integrated 164 RNA-sequencing (RNA-seq) samples from 64 tumours and 234 tumour-infiltrating lymphocyte (TIL) histopathology estimates (hereafter, pathology TIL estimates) from 83 tumours to produce a combined cohort of 258 tumour regions from 88 prospectively acquired tumours within the ‘Tracking Non-Small-Cell Lung Cancer Evolution through Therapy’(TRACERx) 100 cohort</p><h1 id="Results"><a href="#Results" class="headerlink" title="Results"></a>Results</h1><h2 id="Heterogeneity-of-immune-infiltration"><a href="#Heterogeneity-of-immune-infiltration" class="headerlink" title="Heterogeneity of immune infiltration"></a>Heterogeneity of immune infiltration</h2><h3 id="benchmarked-published-in-silico-immune-deconvolution-tools"><a href="#benchmarked-published-in-silico-immune-deconvolution-tools" class="headerlink" title="benchmarked published in silico immune deconvolution tools"></a>benchmarked published in silico immune deconvolution tools</h3><p>The genes used in each one of the immune-estimation approaches were tested to see whether they fit two criteria: (1) having a negative relationship with tumour purity, as genes that define immune subtypes are expressed in infiltrating immune cells and (2) not showing a positive correlation with tumour copy number at the gene locus (a positive correlation may indicate that the gene is expressed by the tumour cell, which would confound immune estimates) </p><p> <img src="https://upload-images.jianshu.io/upload_images/10636424-5b0dc8936c1251fc.png?imageMogr2/auto-orient/" alt="Determination of robust immune infiltration approach "></p><p>for each method, the immune estimates themselves were compared against independent ground-truth measures </p><p><img src="C:\Users\feng\AppData\Roaming\Typora\typora-user-images\1553955582218.png" alt></p><p>&nbsp;</p><p><strong>conclusion</strong>: Compared to other transcriptomic approaches, the <strong>Danaher et al. immune signature</strong> optimally estimated immune infiltrates in NSCLC </p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;[Neoantigen-directed immune escape in lung cancer evolution] (&lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-019-1032-7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-019-1032-7&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;Topic&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Topic&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Topic&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Topic&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;To determine immune infiltration in untreated non-small-cell lung cancer (NSCLC), assess how this infiltration varies between and within tumours, and characterize immune-evasion mechanisms and their associations with clinical outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="paper" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/paper/"/>
    
    
      <category term="cancer" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/cancer/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>SCENIC</title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/2019/03/30/SCENIC/"/>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/2019/03/30/SCENIC/</id>
    <published>2019-03-30T12:31:24.000Z</published>
    <updated>2019-04-13T11:37:30.836Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nmeth.4463" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SCENIC: Single-cell regulatory network inference and clustering</a></p><h2 id="Abstract"><a href="#Abstract" class="headerlink" title="Abstract"></a>Abstract</h2><p>SCENIC can be use to demonstrate <strong>genomic regulatory code</strong> which can be exploited to guide the identification of transcription factors and cell states.</p><a id="more"></a><h2 id="Introduction"><a href="#Introduction" class="headerlink" title="Introduction"></a>Introduction</h2><p>The transcriptional state of a cell emerges from an underlying gene regulatory network (GRN) in which a limited number of transcription factors and co-factors regulate each other and their downstream target genes.</p><p>One challenge of single cell transcriptome profile analysis is that at the single cell level, gene expression may be partially disconnected from the dynamics of transcription factor inputs due to stochastic variation of gene expression consecutive to, for example, transcriptional bursting<br>(基因的表达式动态的，不稳定的)</p><blockquote><p>Transcriptional bursting, also known as transcriptional pulsing, is a fundamental property of genes in which transcription from DNA to RNA can occur in “bursts” or “pulses”, which has been observed in diverse organisms, from bacteria to mammals<br>(from wikipedia)</p></blockquote><p>SCENIC link genomic regulatory code to single-cell gene expression variation to overcome drop-outs and technical variation, and could optimize the discovery and characterization of cellular states</p><p>The SCENIC workflow consists of three steps</p><h2 id="Use-GENIE3-to-identify-sets-of-genes-that-are-co-expressed-with-transcription-factors"><a href="#Use-GENIE3-to-identify-sets-of-genes-that-are-co-expressed-with-transcription-factors" class="headerlink" title="Use GENIE3 to identify sets of genes that are co-expressed with transcription factors"></a>Use <em>GENIE3</em> to identify sets of genes that are co-expressed with transcription factors</h2><p> (<em>GRNboost</em> was also provided to build the co-expression network on bigger datasets)</p><p>In brief, it trains <strong>random forest models</strong> predicting the expression of each gene in the dataset, using as input the expression of the transcription factors.The different models are then used to <strong>derive weights</strong> for the transcription factors, measuring their respective relevance for the prediction of the expression of each target gene. The highest weights can be translated into TF-target regulatory links.</p><p><strong>Input</strong><br>The preferred expression values are gene-summarized counts (which might or might not use unique molecular identifiers, UMI). Other measurements, such as counts or transcripts per million (TPM) and FPKM/RPKM, are also accepted as input. However, note that some authors recommend <strong>avoiding within sample normalization (i.e. TPM) for co-expression analysis because they may induce artificial co-variation</strong></p><p><strong>output</strong><br>The output of GENIE3 is a table with the genes, the potential regulators, and their<br>“importance measure” (IM), which represents the weight that the transcription factor (input gene) has in the prediction of the target.<br> Each gene-set was then split into positive- and negative- correlated targets (i.e. Spearman correlation between the TF and the potential target) to separate likely activated and repressed targets. Finally, only the gene-sets (TF co-expression modules) with <strong>at least 20 genes</strong> were kept for the following step</p><p>Being based only on co-expression, these modules may include many false positives and indirect targets. So <em>RcisTarge</em> was used.</p><h2 id="Use-RcisTarge-to-identify-putative-direct-binding-targets-from-co-expression-module"><a href="#Use-RcisTarge-to-identify-putative-direct-binding-targets-from-co-expression-module" class="headerlink" title="Use RcisTarge to identify putative direct-binding targets from co-expression module"></a>Use <em>RcisTarge</em> to identify putative direct-binding targets from co-expression module</h2><p>Only modules with significant motif enrichment of the correct upstream regulator are retained, and pruned to remove indirect target genes without motif support.<br>Reson:</p><p><strong>Step1</strong><br>It selects DNA motifs that are significantly over-represented in the surroundings of the transcription start site (TSS) of the genes in the gene-set.The motifs that are annotated to the corresponding TF and obtain a Normalized Enrichment Score (NES) &gt; 3.0 are retained. For each species,  two gene-motif rankings (10kb around the TSS or 500bp upstream the TSS), which determine the search space around the transcription start site were used.</p><p><strong>Step2</strong><br>For each motif and gene-set, RcisTarget predicts candidate target genes (i.e. genes in the gene-set that are ranked above the leading edge).</p><blockquote><p>However, in the datasets we analyzed, these modules were less numerous and showed very low motif enrichment, suggesting that these are lower quality modules. For this reason, we finally decided to exclude the detection of direct repression from the workflow, and <strong>continue only with the positive-correlated targets</strong>. </p></blockquote><h2 id="Score-the-activity-of-each-of-these-regulons-in-each-cell-with-AUCell"><a href="#Score-the-activity-of-each-of-these-regulons-in-each-cell-with-AUCell" class="headerlink" title="Score the activity of each of these regulons in each cell with AUCell"></a>Score the activity of each of these regulons in each cell with <em>AUCell</em></h2><p>The relative scores of each regulon across the cells allow identifying which cells have a significantly high sub-network activity. The resulting binary activity matrix can be used as a biological dimensionality reduction for downstream analyses. Since the regulon is scored as a whole, instead of only the TF or individual genes, this approach is robust against drop-outs.</p><p>The input to AUCell is a gene set, and the output the gene set “activity” (AUC) in each cell.</p><p>AUCell calculates the enrichment of the regulon as an area under the recovery curve (AUC) across the ranking of all genes in a particular cell, whereby genes are ranked by their expression value. This method is therefore <strong>independent of the gene expression units and the normalization procedure</strong></p><h2 id="Cell-clustering-based-on-GRNs"><a href="#Cell-clustering-based-on-GRNs" class="headerlink" title="Cell clustering based on GRNs"></a>Cell clustering based on GRNs</h2><p>2 matrix<br>The cell-regulon activity is summarized in a matrix in which the columns represent the cells and the rows the regulons. In the binary <strong>regulon activity matrix</strong>, the coordinates of the matrix that correspond to active regulons in a given cell will contain a “1”, and “0” otherwise.</p><p>The <strong>equivalent matrix</strong>, containing the continuous AUC values for each cell- regulon, is normally referred to as the AUC activity matrix.</p><p>The binary activity matrix tends to highlight higher-order similarities across cells (and therefore, highly reduces batch effects and technical biases), on the other hand, the AUC matrix allows to observe more subtle changes.</p><h2 id="Gene-filtering"><a href="#Gene-filtering" class="headerlink" title="Gene filtering"></a>Gene filtering</h2><p><strong>first filter</strong><br>The total number of reads per gene, is meant to remove genes that are most likely unreliable and provide only noise. The specific value depends on the dataset.</p><p><strong>second filter</strong><br>The number of cells in which the gene is detected (e.g. &gt;0 UMI, or &gt;1 log2(TPM)), is to avoid that genes that are only expressed in one, or very few cells, gain a lot of weight if they happen to coincide in a given cell. In the workflow, we recommend to set a percentage lower than the smallest population of cells to be detected</p><p><img src="https://upload-images.jianshu.io/upload_images/10636424-8f13717bcb851399.png?imageMogr2/auto-orient/strip%7CimageView2/2/w/1240" alt="The SCENIC workflow and its application"></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/nmeth.4463&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;SCENIC: Single-cell regulatory network inference and clustering&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Abstract&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Abstract&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Abstract&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;SCENIC can be use to demonstrate &lt;strong&gt;genomic regulatory code&lt;/strong&gt; which can be exploited to guide the identification of transcription factors and cell states.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="paper" scheme="http://yoursite.com/categories/paper/"/>
    
    
      <category term="methods" scheme="http://yoursite.com/tags/methods/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
